## **Rob Strasser**

## Software Engineer

robstrasserdev@gmail.com • (925) 549-1803 • https://robstrass.github.io/

## CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 2 years as a Software Engineer with startup & global companies in the Networking space
Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Redux, Express, Node.js, Python, Flask, HTML, CSS
Tools Postman, Git, Azure DevOps, JIRA, NSX, vRealize, PostgreSQL, CosmosDB, Docker

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Munich Re

Software Engineer, Network Automation (Contract)

Remote (London, UK)

02/2023 – 12/2023

Software Engineer, Network Automation (Contract)
Technologies: TypeScript, JavaScript, CosmosDB, Azure DevOps, NSX, vRealize, Postman

- Part of a 5 person team in a contract role delivering internal tooling to facilitate Network Automation workflows, serving 40,000+ employees, releasing weekly or bimonthly updates in a CI/CD cycle on a codebase with over 113,000 lines of code
- Built a workflow leveraging multiple APIs to automate the process of cleaning the database, NSX
  environments, and vCenters of network segments and virtual machines, reducing manual efforts from 1-3 days
  to 1-hour maximum
- Patched, tested, and re-developed 12+ automation workflows delivered in a non-functioning state by an
  external team, identifying dozens of critical bugs that would have brought down Production or left internal
  applications vulnerable
- Collaborated with 20+ people from 3 different teams spread across the UK, Germany and Moldova, overcoming time differences of 8-10 hours, to overcome barriers and achieve project goals by identifying key decision-makers and project owners within the organization
- Performed code reviews for 5+ team members on at least a weekly basis, ensuring strict code standards and company policies were met while also personally accounting for 2-4 items per release
- Contract ended due to EOY budget constraints

SPJ Solutions Remote (Sacramento, CA)

Software Engineer 04/2022 - 10/2022

Technologies: Typescript, React, Redux, Express, Node.js, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, NSX, Postman

- Part of a 15+ person startup development team working on an application that managed the migration of clients' networking environments, handling the migration of 5000+ virtual machines, serving 100+ clients
- Appointed sole developer of large micro-segmentation feature that took a snapshot of clients' existing network environment's firewall, organizing and deploying migration in 8 steps to the latest version of NSX
- Developed an algorithm to sort, order, and move 4,000+ custom firewall rules which decreased time spent manually organizing by 90%
- Participated in an Agile development environment consisting of regular code reviews, monthly releases,
   bi-monthly hotfixes, and weekly end-to-end testing on a code base of 80,000+ lines of code
- Laid off as 1 of 10 employees following company restructuring

2017-2021: Asset Protection Supervisor, team of 8 employees. SDR, met 120% of quota. Learned client leadership & time management

**PROJECTS** 

Incapables - <u>live</u> | <u>github</u> 12/2021

Technologies: Javascript, React, Redux, Python, Flask, HTML, CSS, Docker, AWS s3

 Solo project that implemented AWS s3 for scalable image uploads, Redux for efficient state management, and Docker for consistent, scalable deployment

**EDUCATION & ACCREDITATIONS** 

App Academy Coding Bootcamp CSU East Bay - BS Criminal Justice 07/2021 - 01/2022 09/2013-06/2017